Guide to the Ram's Head Records SC0059
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Ram's Head records
1924-2011
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Ram's Head (Stanford, Calif.)
SC0059
13.5 Linear Feet (20 boxes)
Custodial History note
Materials in the collection were given to the Stanford University Archives by Ram's Head in 1969, 2011, and 2012. Gift of Frances Stack, 2016; Blossom Parke McBrier, 2016.
Information about Access
Access: The collection is open for research. Materials are stored off-site and must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of use.
Historical Note
Ram's Head Theatrical Society was organized in 1911 by Payson Jackson Treat, history professor, two other faculty members and seven students. It started as an elite, all-male honorary drama group. Later, a female counterpart known as the Ewe's Head was formed. In the 1930's, the two groups merged. Ram's Head folded in 1971 due to financial problems. It was reorganized in 1975 by Jon Mills and George McMillan with financial support from various university departments and offices. The Ram's Head produces three shows a year: Big Game Gaities, Winter-One-Acts, and the Spring Musical.
Scope and Content
Records of the student drama group Ram's Head include financial reports (1924-1957), Dramatic Council minutes (1925-1948), board minutes, (1935-1957), general correspondence (1934-1952), production books (1937-1959), and several LP records and audio tapes for such Ram's Head productions as the Big Game Gaieties, Winter-One-Acts, and Spring Shows. Also included are files from the Ram's Head web site captured by University Archives staff. Accession ARCH-2012-016 includes programs and posters from productions between 1998 and 2011.
Ram's Head (Stanford, Calif.)
- Financial Records
  - Financial Report, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Financial Report, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Financial Report, 1926-27 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Financial Report, 1927-28 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Financial Report, 1928-29 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Financial Report, 1929-30 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Financial Report, 1930-31 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Financial Report, 1931-32 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Financial Report, 1932-33 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Financial Report, 1933-34 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Financial Report, 1934-35 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Financial Report, 1935-36 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Financial Report, 1936-37 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Financial Report, 1937-38 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Financial Report, 1938-39 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Financial Report, 1939-40 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Financial Report, 1940-41 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Financial Report, 1942-43 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Financial Report, 1943-44 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Financial Report, 1945-46 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Financial Report, 1946-47 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Financial Report, 1947-48 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Financial Report, 1948-49 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Financial Committee Minutes, 1948-49 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Business Manager's Report, 1949-50 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Business Manager's Report, 1950-51 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Business Manager's Report, 1951-52 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Business Manager's Report, 1952-53 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Business Manager's Report, 1953-54 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Business Manager's Report, 1954-55 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Business Manager's Report, 1955-56 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Business Manager's Report, 1956-57 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Treasurers Book, 1953-57 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Administrative Records
  - Dramatic Council Minutes, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Dramatic Council Minutes, 1926-27 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Dramatic Council Minutes, 1933-34 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Dramatic Council Minutes, 1934-35 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Dramatic Council Minutes, 1935-36 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Dramatic Council Minutes, 1936-37 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Dramatic Council Minutes, 1937-38 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Dramatic Council Minutes, 1938-39 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Dramatic Council Minutes, 1939-40 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Dramatic Council Minutes, 1940-41 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Dramatic Council Minutes, 1941-42 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Report of Dramatic Manager, 1941-42 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Dramatic Council Minutes, 1942-43 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Dramatic Council Report, 1942-43 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Dramatic Council Minutes, 1943-44 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Dramatic Council Minutes, 1944-45 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Dramatic Council Report, 1944-45 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Dramatic Council Minutes, 1945-46 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Dramatic Council Minutes, 1946-47 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Dramatic Council Minutes, 1947-48 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Board Minutes, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Board Minutes, 1936-1936 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Board Minutes, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Board Minutes, 1936-37 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Board Minutes, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Board Minutes, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Board Minutes, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Board Minutes, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Board Minutes, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Board Minutes, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Board Minutes, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Board Minutes, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Board Minutes, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Board Minutes, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Board Minutes, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Board Minutes, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Board Minutes, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Board Minutes, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Board Minutes, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - General Correspondence, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - General Correspondence, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - General Correspondence, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - General Correspondence, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - General Correspondence, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - General Correspondence, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - General Correspondence, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - General Correspondence, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - General Correspondence, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Ram's Head Room, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Board By-Laws, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Gaieties, assorted records, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Production Records
  - Production Book: Spring Show, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Production Book: Winter One-Acts, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Production Book: Spring Show, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Production Book: Winter One-Acts, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Production Book; Gaieties., 1943 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Production Book: Gaieties, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Production Book: Spring Show, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Production Book: Gaieties, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Production Book: Winter One-Acts, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Production Book: Gaieties, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Production Book: Winter One-Acts, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Production Book: Spring Show, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Production Book: Gaieties, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Production Book: Spring Show, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Production Book: Gaieties, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Production Book: Winter One-Acts, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Production Book: Spring Show, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Production Book: Winter One-Acts, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Production Book: Spring Show, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Production Book (a): Gaieties, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Production Book (b): Gaieties, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Production Book (a): Spring Show, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Production Book (b): Spring Show, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Production Book (c): Spring Show, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Production Book (a): Gaieties, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Production Book (b): Gaieties, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Production Book (a): Spring Show, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Production Book (b): Spring Show, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Production Book (a): Gaieites, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Production Book (b): Gaieties, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Production Book (a): Winter One-Acts, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Production Book (b): Winter One-Acts, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Production Book (a): Spring Show, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Production Book (b): Spring Show, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Production Book (a): Gaieties, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Production Book (b): Gaieties, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Production Book (a): Winter One-Acts, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Production Book (b): Winter One-Acts, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Production Book (a): Spring Show, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Production Book (b): Spring Show, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Production Book (c): Spring Show, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Production Book (d): Spring Show, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Production Book: Gaieties, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Gaieties, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Production Book (a): Winter One-Acts, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Production Book (b): Winter One-Acts, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Production Book (a): Spring Show, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Production Book (b): Spring Show, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Production Book (a): Gaieties, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Production Book (b): Gaieties, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Reports, Spring Show, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Directors Report, Gaieties, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Production Book (a): Spring Show, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Production Book: Gaieties, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Production Book (a): Spring Show, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Production Book (b): Spring Show, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Production Book (c): Spring Show, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Call Me Madam, 1958 Spring (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Production Book (a): Gaieties, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Production Book (b): Gaieties, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Production Book (a): Los Angeles Road-show, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Production Book (b): Los Angeles Road-show, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Production Book: Winter One-Acts, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Production Book: Spring Shows, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Pal Joey, 1959 Spring (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Production Book (a): Gaieties, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Production Book (b): Gaieties, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Production Book (c): Gaieties, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook from Spring Show "No Mother to Guide Her" (script, stage directions, program, and some related correspondence), 1943 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Assorted programs, 1955-1956 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Programs (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Gaieties, lighting plan, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Gaieties, lighting rehearsal notes, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Gaieties, lighting notes, circa 1955 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Gaieties, lighting plan, 1956 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Gaieties programs, 1954-1957 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous records (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Spring Show, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Waiting for Lefty, lighting plan, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Of Thee I Sing, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Music
  - Spring Show music, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Spring Show music, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Spring Show music, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Spring Show music, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Gaieties music, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Ram's Head music, miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 6-10)
  - Spring Show music, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 2-4)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2004-326
  - Gaieties material, 1948 (Box 1)
- Audiovisual Material
  - Big Game Gaieties sound track, 1954; 1 audio disc(s) (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Big Game Gaieties sound track, 1954; 1 audio disc(s) (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Big Game Gaieties sound track, 1955; 1 audio disc(s) (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Big Game Gaieties sound track, 1955; 1 audio disc(s) (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Big Game Gaieties sound track, 1956; 1 audio disc(s) (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Big Game Gaieties sound track, 1957; 1 audio disc(s) (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Big Game Gaieties sound track, 1963; 1 audio disc(s) (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Big Game Gaieties sound track, 1964; 1 audio disc(s) (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Big Game Gaieties sound track, 1965; 1 audio disc(s) (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Big Game Gaieties sound track, 1966; 1 audio disc(s) (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Big Game Gaieties sound track, 1967; 1 audio disc(s) (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Knight in Arms (Spring Show) sound track, 1961; 1 audio disc(s) (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Pal Joey, 1959; 3 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 12, Folder 17)
- Programs, Accession ARCH-2012-016
  - Programs from various productions, circa 1998-2011; 31 item(s) (Box 13)
- Posters, Accession ARCH-2012-016
  - Posters from various productions, circa 1998-2011; 32 item(s) (Box 14)
- Website Files, 2011; 165 megabyte(s) (2655 files in 4671 folders)
  - 2011 December 6
- Additional Records, Accession ARCH-2016-123
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Materials in this series donated by Blossom Parke McBrier, 2016.
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists primarily of materials relating to the 1943 Gaities production.
  - "Just a Plaything," sheet music, 1942 Oct 8 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Pin up Girl," lyrics (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Finale," sheet music and lyrics (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Pin up Girl," sheet music (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "L.S.M.F.T.," skit on Frank Sinatra (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Clippings re Gaities, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Gaities poster (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Additional Records, Accession ARCH-2016-130
  - Spring Show poster, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Gaieties poster, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Gaieties poster, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Additional Records, Accession ARCH-2018-035
  - Gaieties, 1977; 1 videotape(s) (Box 1)